Eric Mauldin

- Web Developer -

tel: 706.372.1536

email: emauldin84@gmail.com portfolio: ericmauldin.info

LinkedIn: <u>linkedin.com/in/ericmauldin</u> GitHub: github.com/emauldin84

Creative web developer with the ability to pick up new languages and technologies as needed. Prior to becoming a web developer, I worked as a director of transportation for an Atlanta Destination Management Company where I managed complex logistics programs for Fortune 500s visiting the Atlanta area, providing clients with support and consultation for their specific needs.

EXPERIENCE

Developer in Residence (Teaching Assistant)

DigitalCrafts, Atlanta, GA | Oct. 2019-Dec. 2019

- Assist lead senior developer in educating & mentoring students in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node.js, PostgreSQL, and React/Redux.
- Responsibilities include regular student check-in's, personalized coaching, lead an hour of instruction every Friday covering debugging, algorithms, white-boarding, and interview prep.

Immersive Full-Stack Web Developer Coding Bootcamp

DigitalCrafts, Atlanta, GA | Feb. 2019-May 2019

- 16-week, hands-on software development program covering HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, Node.js, Express, PostgreSQL, React, Redux, and AWS. My DigitalCrafts projects include:
- Flamingo <u>flamingo.ericmauldin.info</u> team project React, Node.js full stack web application utilizing Express, PostgreSQL, Vanilla JavaScript, Materialize, CSS, Axios. Flamingo is a mobile-first, digital interpretation of a familiar way of showing trips across the globe. Users can quickly add, delete and edit past and future trips, creating and saving travel experiences.
- **C's Recipes** <u>cs-recipes.ericmauldin.info</u> A personal React project built out of my fiancée's need to manage her recipes. The idea was to build a simple interface to allow the user to add, search, view, edit and delete recipes. The backend is built using node and express accessing a PostgreSQL database.

Director of Transportation

Presenting Atlanta, Atlanta, GA | Sept. 2011–Feb. 2019

- Coordinated complex transportation programs for Fortune 500s
- Consulted clients and Presenting Atlanta's sales team concerning all transportation needs
- Managed and curated a team of 20+ independent contractor staff as well as third party vendors
- Employed precise attention to detail to ensure programs were executed flawlessly and profitably from conception to completion
- Championed efficiency by designing and implementing new productivity tools to simplify and expedite logistics processes

SKILLS

- JavaScript, Node.js, HTML, CSS
- · React, React Native, Express, Bootstrap
- PostgreSQL
- Git, GitHub, VS Code, Postman, AWS, EC2, Chrome Dev Tools, REST APIs
- WordPress
- QuickBooks

SIDE PROJECTS

Creator

BreakerOneNine | Oct. 2016-Oct. 2019

- Created and constructed the CDL employment site, breakeronenine.com
- Collaborated with professional development team for complex site customization

Co-Founder

Club Work | Aug. 2013-Mar. 2015

- Managed launch of online job board, clubwork.com
- Co-created a concise, inclusive and refined recruitment and placement system for matching Private Clubs with experienced prospective employees
- Worked conjointly with a local marketing and web development agency to optimize SEO and conversion rates within the Google AdWords and WordPress platforms

EDUCATION

BBA Management, Terry College of

University of Georgia, Athens, GA | Aug. 2003-May 2008

Coursework focused on Operations management, Organizational behavior, and Strategic management